Preliminary Guide to the Judith McCombs papers, 1989-2008 " MS2265
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Judith McCombs papers
1989-2008
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
McCombs, Judith
MS2265
1 Linear Feet
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Judith McCombs, 2008 (Accession 2008.033).
Arrangement
This collection is not yet processed and series have not yet been determined.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains manuscripts, cover art, correspondence, drafts, critiques, fliers. Much of the material relates to two works by McCombs, Territories and Habit of Fire. The material dates from 1989-2008. There is also a small file for the reading series Kensington Row Bookshop which McCombs runs.
Biographical note
Judith McCombs is the author of three books of poetry, two chapbooks, and as a scholar of Margaret Atwood she has written two books and numerous articles exploring the Atwood's work. As a poet, her poems have appeared in journals such as Calyx, Red Cedar Review, Nimrod, Poetry, Poetry Northwest, and River Styx.
McCombs is a retired Professor from Detroit's Center for Creative Studies College of Art. She has held fellowships from the National Endowment for the Humanities and the Canadian Embassy. In addition, she has received Neruda-Nimrod, Potomac Review, and Maryland State Arts Council poetry awards. She was the poetry editor for the Potomac Review's 2005-06 Hilary Tham tribute issue.
McCombs teaches at the Writer's Center in Bethesda, MD, and coordinates a poetry reading series at Kensington Row Bookshop.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Literature; Poetry; Poets, American; Tham, Hilary; McCombs, Judith
- Habit of Fire book ms, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Habit of Fire Hilary Tham edits, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Habit of Fire Miles Moore, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Habit of Fire Bari Armitage, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Habit of Fire Dan Minock critique, 08/2003 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Habit of Fire Karren Alenier comments, 10/2003-01/2004 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Habit of Fire Cynthia Hoffman, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Habit of Fire almost clean copy, 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Habit of Fire word to Janice Olson book designer, 05/2004 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Habit of Fire blrubs, correspondence Maxine Kumin, Alisia Ostriker, Robert Peters, 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Habit of Fire cover art, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Habit of Fire cover art Jo Ann clayton Townsend, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Habit of Fire fundraising letters, press releases, brochures, 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Habit of Fire galley correspondence, 10/2004-11/2004 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Habit of Fire reviews (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Habit of Fire finalist Kessler poetry book contest and other contests, 2004-2007 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- a:bk 92 Terr p., 1992-1995 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Territories Calyx Books, 1989-1993 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Territories bk finalist Washington Writers Publishing House, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Territories 95 finalist Word Works, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Territories, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Territories, 1998-2000 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Territories Here and Elsewhere, 11/2001 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Book Tries Correspondence, 2002-2003 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Territories Here and Elsewhere, 06/2002-02/2003 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Territories chapbook manuscript, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- After the Surveyor's Death chapbook manuscript, 1991-1996 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Bibliography, 1964-2007 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- resume 08 3pp, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Kensington Row Bookshop poetry reading with notes on series for GWU, 2003-2008 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Hilary Tham Poetry Group News Room, 1991-2004 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Spectrum Gallery "Straight Walls", undated (Box 2, Folder 11)